A gust of wind came...
هبت الرياح
The thermos fell over...
وانقلبت الكظيمة
The sandwiches were all dirty...
صارت السندويشات قذرة
At the time, he...
...وساعتها
just smiled sadly...
كان فقط يبتسم بحزن
Do you want one too, lady?
هل تريدين يا عمتي؟
Hey, Franz!
!مهلًا (فرانز)
That's rude!
!كن مهذبًا
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Is it good?
لذيذ؟
Start walking.
امشيا
Get in.
اصعدا
Oh, hello?
مرحبًا؟
I can't get through to Mr. Verdeman.
لا أستطيع الاتصال بالأستاذ (فارديمان)
That's why I'm calling you.
ولهذا اتصلتُ بك
Oh, his wife just gave birth, so he's probably still at the maternity center.
أجل، زوجته أنجبت، لا بد أنه في قسم التوليد
I've heard about you, Miss Eva Heinemann.
لقد سمعتُ عنك الكثير، سيدة (إيفا هاينيمان)
Please, feel free to tell me anything you'd like.
أرجو أن تخبريني بكل ما لديكِ دون تردد
I thought I'd talk.
قررتُ أن أتكلم
About what?
حول ماذا؟
The testimony to prove Tenma's innocence.
الشهادة لإثبات براءة (تينما)
I see. We're very grateful!
فهمت، سنكون ممتنين لك
So...
إذًا
what hotel are you staying at right now?
في أي فندق أنتِ الآن؟
Got it.
فهمت
I'll head over there right now.
أنا قادم إليكِ على الفور
The Escape
الفصل 54
With timing like this...
في وقتنا هذا
they'll just go around me and keep driving.
كل ما يفعلونه هو الدوران حولي ومواصلة القيادة
The car comes, right?
السيارة تأتي من هناك
Then I fall.
أنا أسقط هنا
Comes.
تأتي
Fall.
أسقط
This timing should be right.
يجب أن يكون التوقيت صحيحًا
Comes.
تأتي
Fall.
أسقط
Fall.
ألا تسمعني؟
What? I'm in the middle of something.
ماذا تريدين؟ أنا مشغول جدًا
Are you really going to marry me today?
هل حقًا ستتزوجني هذا اليوم؟
How many times do I have to tell you?
كم مرة علي إخبارك؟
I will.
سوف أفعل
You really will?
ستفعل حقًا؟
Swear to God?
هل تقسم بالله؟
Yeah.
أجل
I'll swear to anything you want today, Helene.
سأقسم على أي شيء تريدينه اليوم يا (هيليني)
Then kiss me, Gustav.
إذًا قبلني يا (غوستاف)
Let's continue this in the car.
هيا لنواصل داخل السيارة
Hey! Wait! Stop!
!مهلًا! توقفي
Now's not the time for this!
!الوقت غير مناسب لهذا
You used my drugs again?
استعملتِ من مخدراتي مجددًا؟
That was the last of my stash!
!هذه كانت آخر مدخراتي
Wasn't me!
!لست أنا
No wonder your nose is running, bitch!
!لهذا أنفك يسيل أيتها العاهرة
I'm out here practicing for my job while you're in here snorting my stuff?!
أنا في الخارج أتدرب على عملي بينما أنتِ تستهلكين مدخراتي
What job? It's simple.
أي عمل؟ إنه سهل
All you're doing is lying in the road.
كل ما تفعله هو الارتماء على الشارع
Simple?!
سهل؟
Easy for you to say!
!سهل عليك أن تقولي هذا
If I mess up even a little, I'll die!
!أي خطأ صغير قد ينتهي بموتي
You're going to die?
هل ستموت؟
Isn't it obvious?!
أليس هذا واضحًا؟
I'd be killed instantly
سأموت على الفور
- I don't want you to die!
!لا أريدك أن تموت
- No, that was just an example...
لا، كان ذلك مجرد مثال فقط
Gustav's gonna die!
!غوستاف) سيموت)
I won't die.
لن أموت
There are still some things I have to do.
هناك أشياء كثيرة يجب علي فعلها
Like what?
ما هي؟
I've gotta have lots of kids with you.
سأنجب منك الكثير من الأطفال
We're going to make a whole soccer team with our kids.
سنشكل فريق كرة قدم كاملًا من أطفالنا
That's so wonderful, Gustav.
هذا رائع (غوستاف)
I'll be getting a load of cash from the job I'm about to do.
سأحصل على أموال كثيرة من العمل الذي أقوم به
Then we'll get married.
وعندها سنتزوج
You'll make my dream come true, right, Helene?
ستجعلين حلمي يتحول إلى حقيقة، (هيليني)؟
Oh, Gustav!
!(غوستاف)
I'll have them! I'll have them!
!هيا! هيا
I'll have as many babies as you want!
سأنجب لك قدر ما تشاء من الأطفال
I keep telling you, now is not the time for that!
!قلتُ لكِ أن الوقت ليس مناسبًا لهذا
No, I want to make babies!
!لكني أريد إنجاب أطفال
Be patient for now.
اصبري الآن
It's almost time for a "Detective Forster" rerun.
إنه تقريبًا وقت إعادة (المحقق فورستر)
The car comes.
السيارة قادمة
I jump out.
سأرتمي
I fall down.
وأسقط
The car comes.
السيارة قادمة
I jump out.
سأرتمي
I fall down.
وأسقط
The car comes.
السيارة قادمة
I jump out.
سأرتمي
I fall down.
وأسقط
The car comes...
السيارة قادمة
I'm thinking of killing someone.
أنا أفكر في قتل شخص ما
Your former fiancée...
خطيبتك السابقة
Eva Heinemann.
(إيفا هاينيمان)
Don't...
...لا
Don't!
!لا
Stop!
!توقف
It's so nice out.
الطقس جميل في الخارج
Such nice weather, yet I'm stuck in a car like this.
طقس جميل وأنا محشور في سيارة كهذه
With this damn serial killer, no less.
مع قاتل متسلسل لعين
Man, I'm so unlucky.
يا لحظي التعس
Stop talking, Milch!
!كف عن الكلام، (ميلش)
But you're lucky.
لكنك محظوظ
In this gloomy little prison van...
في شاحنة السجن الكئيبة هذه
on your way to some dank detention facility...
في طريقك إلى منشأة سجنية رطبة
you get to hear plenty of stories about the twelve escapes of the master escapee, Gunther Milch.
ستستمع للكثير من القصص حول الهروبات الاثني عشر لسيد الهرب (غونتر ميلش)
Now then, which should I start with?
حسنًا بأيها أبدأ الآن؟
The one about how I escaped from Kreiner Prison is the best.
قصة هربي من سجن (كراينر) هي الأفضل
Shut up!
!قلتُ لك اخرس
Come on. I'm just bored.
أنا فقط أشعر بالملل
What time is it?
كم الساعة الآن؟
I asked you for the time.
لقد سألتُك كم الساعة
It's 9:32.
إنها الـ 9:32
If I were out in the free world...
لو كنتُ في الخارج
it'd almost be time for a rerun of "Detective Forster" on TV.
لقد اقترب موعد عرض إعادة (المحقق فورستر) على التلفاز
Did you ever watch that show?
هل شاهدتَ ذلك العرض؟
It's really good.
إنه رائع جدًا
All right, it's almost time.
حسنًا يوشك أن يصل الوقت
I'm gonna take care of this little job real quick.
سأذهب لأنهي هذه المهمة الصغيرة بسرعة
You just watch me work from here.
أنتِ فقط راقبيني أعمل من هنا
A gun...
!مسدس
Are you going to shoot it?
هل ستطلق النار؟
I won't.
لن أفعل
I'm just gonna use it to scare them.
سأستعمله فقط لإخافتهم
I don't want our kids to have murderers for parents!
!لا أريد لأبنائنا أن يكونوا من أبوين مجرمين
Don't shoot anyone!
!لا تطلق على أحد
I'll even stop using drugs!
!سأتوقف عن استهلاك المخدرات
I love you, Helene.
أنا أحبك يا (هيليني)
I've really decided!
لقد قررتُ حقًا
Let's get married!
!لنتزوج
Really?
حقًا؟
We're gonna live honestly from now on.
سنعيش حياة شريفة بدءًا من اليوم
I won't do jobs where I have to wave a gun around anymore.
لن أقوم بأي عمل يتطلب التلويح بمسدس
Really?
حقًا؟
Yeah.
أجل
Nothing good comes from waving around things like this.
لا خير يأتي من التلويح بهذه الأشياء
Gustav!
!(غوستاف)
Ah! This feels so great, damn it!
!يا له من شعور رائع، اللعنة
Helene!
(هيليني)
What is it?
ماذا؟
I love you from the bottom of my...
...أنا أحبك من أعماق
W-What was that?!
ما الأمر؟
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
I...
لقد... صدمتُ أحدًا
What?!
ماذا تقول؟
You... hit someone?
صدمتَ أحدًا؟
Sit down, Milch!
!ميلش)، اجلس)
You... hit him?
صدمتَ... أحدًا؟
Didn't you hear me? Sit down, Milch!
ألم تسمعني؟ قلتُ لك اجلس يا (ميلش)
That was probably my little brother...
يبدو أنه أخي الأصغر
The plan... failed, Dr. Tenma...
الخطة... فشلت، طبيب (تينما)
I taught Gustav the timing and acting over and over again...
لقد أخبرتُ (غوستاف) بالتوقيت وبما عليه أن يفعله
but in the end, nobody can do it as well as me.
لكن في النهاية لا أحد يستطيع إتقان ذلك مثلي
I asked him to pass out on the road like he was sick...
طلبتُ منه أن يرتمي في الشارع متظاهرًا بالمرض
so he could stop the oncoming car...
وبهذا تتوقف السيارة القادمة
He's really bad, so you should've just avoided him and kept going...
كان عليك أن تتجاوزه وتواصل سيرك
And yet... and yet...
...لكن، لكن
why did you have to go and hit him?
لماذا كان عليك أن تصدمه؟
I don't really get what you're saying, but...
...لا أفهم حقًا ما تقول
go check and see if it's someone you know or not!
لكن، تعال لتؤكد لنا ما إذا كنتَ تعرفه أم لا
Gustav...
(غوستاف)
Oh, Gustav...
...(غوستاف)
Helene...
(هيليني)
This isn't good...
...هذا سيئ
I-Is he still breathing...
أما زال يتنفس؟
E-Excuse me, but we have a doctor right here.
لحظة، لدينا طبيب هنا بالفعل
Hey, you.
أنت، تعال
Get out.
اخرج
Hey!
!أنت
Gustav's dead...
...غوستاف) مات)
H-How is he?
كيف هو؟
Is he alive?
ما زال حيًا؟
How could I have done this?
ماذا فعلتُ؟
I've totally failed...
...يا لها من مأساة
Gustav!
!(غوستاف)
Oh, man...
...تبًا
Maybe we should tell him to cover it up in the report...
يبدو أن علينا إخفاء الأمر من التقرير
How can we cover up something like this?
كيف سنستطيع إخفاء أمر كهذا؟
I know, but...
...لا، لكن
The keys!
!المفاتيح
Give me the keys to the handcuffs!
!ناولوني مفاتيح الأصفاد
Are you waiting for someone?
هل تنتظرين أحدًا؟
Yes.
نعم
Would you like anything to drink?
هل تريدين شرب شيء؟
A Scotch.
(سكوتش)
No, wait.
لا
A cup of coffee.
قهوة
In our next story....
نشرة الأخبار
A fire struck a large shopping mall in Dortmund today.
شب حريق اليوم في مركز تسوق كبير في دورتمند
Thanks to the employees triggering the fire alarm, the blaze was brought under control...
وبفضل العمال الذين أعلنوا حالة الطوارئ تمت السيطرة على الحريق
but two stores were completely lost.
لكن متجرين احترقا تمامًا
- There have been no reported injuries.
لم يتم الإعلان عن أية إصابات
- I thought I'd talk.
قررتُ أن أتكلم
About what?
حول ماذا؟
The testimony to prove Tenma's innocence.
الشهادة لإثبات براءة (تينما)
Got it.
فهمت
I'll head over there right now.
أنا قادم إليكِ على الفور
Please wait in the hotel lobby.
انتظريني في ردهة الفندق
What are you trying to do by setting that man free?
ما الذي تحاول فعله بإثبات براءة ذلك الرجل؟
This just came in.
نعود لنواصل نشرة الأخبار
At 10 o'clock this morning, in a suburb of Düsseldorf, Erkrath...
في العاشرة من صباح هذا اليوم، وفي واحدة من ضواحي ديسلدورف
two prisoners who were being transported to the Hilden Detention Facility escaped from police custody.
هرب سجينان من شاحنة الشرطة أثناء نقلهما إلى مؤسسة هيلدن السجنية
No details have been reported, but....
...لم نتوصل بأية تفاصيل حول الحادث لكن
the two fugitives who escaped were....
...السجينان الهاربان هما
Gunther Milch, arrested for armored car robbery...
الموقوف بسبب نهب السيارات، غونتر ميلش
and the serial killer, Kenzo Tenma.
وأيضًا، القاتل المتسلسل كينزو تينما
The police have been deployed...
رجال الشرطة انتشروا
and are now tracking down the two fugitives.
وهم الآن يمسحون المكان بحثًا عن الهاربين
Why?
لماذا؟
Why did you escape?
لماذا هربتَ؟
Yes, hello?
نعم، مرحبًا؟
Oh, Mr. Verdeman.
السيد (فارديمان)
Yes, I heard the news.
نعم، سمعتُ الأخبار
Why did you have to escape?
لم كان عليك أن تهرب؟
I...
...أنا
Just when I was about to prove your innocence...
وحين كنتُ على وشك إثبات براءتك
Why?
لماذا؟
Well, it's no use asking me about it.
حسنًا لا داعي لسؤالي حول ذلك
I don't understand his motives either.
أنا لم أفهم دوافعه بعد
Yes.
نعم
For now, let's just head over to the police station.
لنتوجه الآن فقط نحو مركز الشرطة
However...
...لكن
the truth is, there's something that I have to take care of first.
وفي الحقيقة، هناك أمر علي إتمامه أولًا
I see.
فهمت
Yes. Yes. That's true.
أجل، نعم، صحيح
We must both deal with the current situation calmly.
يجب أن نتعامل معًا مع هذا الوضع بهدوء
Yes.
أجل
Yes, I completely agree.
أجل، أتفق معك تمامًا
That voice...
...هذا الصوت
In any case, we have to get the details.
مهما يكن، يجب أن نحصل على التفاصيل
Yes.
أجل
That voice...
...هذا الصوت
Yes, it's exactly as you said.
أجل، هو تمامًا كما قلتَ
- Yes, as much as we can. Yes.
أجل، قدر ما نستطيع، أجل
Roberto!
!(روبيرتو)
Here's your coffee...
قهوتك
That's not... my cigarette...
!هذه... ليست سيجارتي
This smell...
!هذه الرائحة
It's that man's smell...
...رائحة ذلك الرجل
He was...
...لقد كان هنا
Roberto was just in this room!
!لقد كان في غرفتي... (روبيرتو)
Gustav!
!(غوستاف)
Gustav's dead!
!مات (غوستاف)
Helene, he's not dead yet.
هيليني)، إنه لم يمت بعد)
But he can't be saved.
لكن لا يمكن إنقاذه
He hit his head, and he's not bleeding.
أصيب رأسه وهو لا ينزف
it's what they call a brain hemorrhage.
وهذا ما يسمونه النزيف الدماغي
Isn't that right, Doctor?
أليس كذلك يا طبيب؟
I understand how you feel, but...
أفهم كيف تشعرين
we're going to change cars at the path through the forest up ahead, like we planned.
سنقوم بتغيير السيارة في ممر الغابة التي نتجه نحوها كما خططنا
Gustav is just a burden.
غوستاف) هو مجرد عبء)
We'll leave him in this car.
سنتركه في هذه السيارة
No!
!لا
keep going!
!واصل السير
We don't have time to change cars.
لا وقت لدينا لتغيير السيارة
You crazy?
هل جننت؟
The cops have seen this car.
الشرطة شاهدوا هذه السيارة
They'll find us in no time!
!سيجدوننا على الفور
If we can get him to a hospital soon...
لو نقلناه إلى مستشفى بسرعة
there's a chance he can be saved!
!فإن هناك فرصة لإنقاذه
A hospital?
مستشفى؟
Doctor, your quick-wittedness saved my escape plan when it was about to fail.
طبيب، سرعة بديهتك أنقذت مخطط هربي حين كان على وشك الفشل
But from now on, you're going to listen to the pro.
لكن الآن، يجب أن تستمع لكلام المحترف
I feel sorry for him, but we'll leave Gustav at the path through the forest up ahead and...
...أنا آسف لأجله، لكننا سنترك (غوستاف) في ممر الغابة
keep driving to the hospital!
!واصل السير إلى المستشفى
Eisler Memorial Hospital
مستشفى (آيسلر) التذكاري
They have the best equipment and staff in Düsseldorf there.
لديهم هناك أفضل فريق طبي في (ديسلدورف)
It's the hospital I worked at!
إنه المستشفى الذي عملتُ فيه
Hurry!
!أسرع
The main entrance to the hospital is just ahead.
المدخل الرئيسي للمستشفى يقع هناك
Stop crying!
لا تبكي
Once you reach the entrance...
حين تصلين إلى المدخل، أخبريهم أن يسلموا هذه الرسالة إلى الطبيب (واغنر)
It contains a detailed description of the accident.
فيها وصف تفصيلي للحادثة
Gustav won't die?
غوستاف) لن يموت؟)
He's still alive!
إنه ما زال حيًا
Don't give up as long as he's still alive!
لا تستسلمي ما دام حيًا
Hurry up and go!
!هيا أسرعي
Now then...
...والآن
if we stick around here any longer...
...إن بقينا نتجول هنا أكثر
it's like we'll be asking to be found.
فكأننا نطلب منهم أن يجدونا
Thanks for your help.
شكرًا لمساعدتك
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
You'd better stick with me.
الأفضل لك أن تبقى معي
You're a complete amateur at this.
أنت مجرد هاوٍ
The life of a woman I know is in danger.
حياة امرأة أعرفها في خطر
I have to get to her as soon as possible.
يجب أن أذهب إليها
A woman?
امرأة؟
You mean to tell me that's why you escaped?
أتريد إخباري بأن هذا هو سبب هربك؟
If you want women, just come with me to Tunisia.
إن أردتَ النساء، فقط تعال معي إلى تونس
You can sleep with as many of the best women as you want.
تستطيع أن تضاجع أي قدر تريد من الجميلات
Thank you.
أشكرك
Goodbye.
وداعًا
Doctor.
طبيب
You haven't really killed anyone, have you?
أنت لم تقتل أحدًا قط صحيح؟
I shot one person...
أطلقتُ على واحد
but he's still alive.
لكنه ما زال حيًا
That's not killing.
هذا ليس قتلًا
As far as that one goes, you're completely innocent.
كنتَ لتتخلص من كل تهمك أمام المحكمة
But you've got a real criminal record now.
لكنك صرتَ الآن مجرمًا حقيقيًا
You're now officially a fugitive.
رسميًا أنت الآن هارب
Let's meet up in Tunisia someday, fugitive to fugitive.
لنلتق في تونس يومًا ما، هارب مع هارب
It's a great place!
!إنها مكان رائع